<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-25T10:04:54-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://SBlines.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number 10]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/10/25/number-10/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-25T09:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/10/25/number-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>End of Week 6</h1>

<p>This week we began front end development. I didn&rsquo;t have much trouble with the CSS and again felt good being able to help others with their pages. I was able to figure most of it out with W3 and Stack Overflow, I didn&rsquo;t want to copy any of the Bootstrap page&rsquo;s code. The CSS-Tricks site in the tutorial helped me a lot, and then after that I just needed to clearfix a few things. That seems to be the solution to many of my HTML problems, along with putting borders around everything. I will try to implement these techniques into non-coding situations as well.</p>

<p>I did better on the Test First JavaScript than the first round of Ruby tests. I have a problem understanding what the test requires but knowing code in general will likely help me figure out things- or at least fail, faster. My brain has been all Ruby lately that I didn&rsquo;t remember much of the JavaScript I did learn before applying to Fullstack and should finish the first Code School JQuery course so that I won&rsquo;t be lost when we start it. First thing is to finish the Rails tutorial because we covered enough throughout the course and I should have it figured out by now.</p>

<p>I like the Game of Life project we&rsquo;re working on. Typing out the code itself has been confusing but I&rsquo;ve been able to get some accurate pseudo-code and plan things out. THe whole thing doesn&rsquo;t seem as intense as something like Rails Starter and I&rsquo;d really like to complete this one.</p>

<p>My group&rsquo;s Rails Starter was never finished. The plan was to stay late this week except we were all staying late anyway to do other things. I can still do some more of it once I get through the Michael Hartl tutorial.</p>

<p>Box is working out for me. I&rsquo;m still learning the basic keyboard shortcuts but can get around without trouble. Besides browsing and command line, I don&rsquo;t know much about Macs in general and  should take a look around the system preferences and all these other things that were pre-installed. Sublime is helpful for coding. I always used Notepad but the things we do here are too extreme for me to have in just one color. Much easier to tell if I spelled a kayword wrong, because the color would be different and I make plenty of typing mistakes on this keyboard.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d choose Ruby over JavaScript right now, which had never been the case. It must be from using it so much that I&rsquo;ve gotten familiar with the way Ruby can be typed up. Overall I feel like my progress is good enough though it would be nice if I were able to fit more free-time studying in during the week. By the time I get back to my apartment I usually can&rsquo;t concentrate well and just look over some of the things we did that week. Weekends I put as much time as I can into the prep work. One thing I haven&rsquo;t done is integrate with the coding community. I don&rsquo;t read or write coding blogs. I did this for HTML in high school, with MySpace friends but have yet to do this with Ruby. Once I get all the information I can through the guides online I&rsquo;ll start dealing with people more directly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number Nine]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/number-nine/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-18T10:08:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/number-nine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>End of Week 5</h1>

<p>I started this week off with a cold on Sunday night. I was being careful to keep my hands clean and not breathe on anything and I think by now I would have known if anyone else became sick. Usually after one night of quality sleep I can recover.</p>

<p>Monday and Tuesday were spent going over the assessment. I felt like I was in bad shape on Friday, after trying to take the test without notes and wanted to be in the review group. I ended up not going to Comic Con on Friday or the release event at Nintendo World because I felt I should review more instead. Despite spending all day at Javits on Saturday and Sunday, I got through most of the Ruby Learn to Program book. Next I need to read-up on Rails.</p>

<p>The review went well, especially teaching it to each other and going over the programs in a way geared towards someone less experienced. Imon was asking questions I would only expect from a non-dev, things like what is a block and what do we need &lsquo;i&rsquo; for, which helped my explanations bring the whole code together. After two days we moved on to the Rails project.</p>

<p>I am slowly figuring out Rails and can see why it&rsquo;s used so often. My plan this weekend is to get through the tutorials and make one or two small things on my own. In the two days we had for our current project, I spent time learning how the different files connect and what is needed to link them together. I had help with the routes file and now know how to embed links. Right now I would choose Ruby over Rails but am willing to put more time into Rails.</p>

<p>Our group worked together well, except for a few small details that we spent too much time arguing on. It reminded me of high school math class where I could say &ldquo;I&rsquo;m right and you probably aren&rsquo;t so we&rsquo;ll do it my way,&rdquo; except I wasn&rsquo;t so confident with my Rails knowledge. We broke into two teams of two, and them Imon and I ended up working by ourselves to finish a few parts. I liked being part of a team. I felt like I really had to get to work and not rely on the other person to correct everything I type. After a few issues I was able to get my job done. I also tried the orders and started to look into Stripe but by Thursday night after the chat our team had slowed down and we didn&rsquo;t work on the project further. I didn&rsquo;t want to leave yet so I worked on Ruby Bits.</p>

<p>I feel much better about my progress this week now that things are coming together. I have also contacted a small startup in Baltimore about a Ruby internship. I might rather get right into the big jobs but if I can learn more while making some money it might work out better to start this way, even take a break from NYC for a few months and see what happens. My buddy lives down there but he&rsquo;s married now so I probably won&rsquo;t be staying with him.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[number 8]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/10/11/number-8/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-11T10:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/10/11/number-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>End of Week 4</h1>

<p>This week has been difficult. If I&rsquo;m able to figure out some of the parts to each program, I still can&rsquo;t piece them all together to see how the whole thing works. So far Ruby has been easier to work with but that could be because I&rsquo;ve had some more time to spend working with it than with Rails. It seems like in the long run I might prefer Rails.</p>

<p>I have been trying to pick apart a Ruby tutorial game, where a ship is moved across the screen to collect items. There are plenty of variables to affect the speed of the ship and generation of stars and I&rsquo;ve been testing them all out, adding in notes to help me remember.</p>

<p>I found that Codeschool will work on Chrome, as Safari wasn&rsquo;t loading theings correctly. Somestimes I would try to do some Zombies on my Mac but the videos wouldn&rsquo;t load. Still working on Ruby Bits but it&rsquo;s been slow because of display problems on Safari. The slides are zoomed-in too much that it&rsquo;s not easy to switch between them while answering the questions. I want to show my younger cousins these courses over the holidays to give them an idea of what coding is.</p>

<p>The Dev Stackup on Tuesday evening was interesting. I liked hearing about the things everyone did at work and what these creations were used for. I start to wonder how many things I use are coded by people nearby. I also liked hearing that places are hiring, which has never been the case since I finished radiology school. That&rsquo;s more of an incentive for me to study and work hard.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post 7]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/10/04/post-7/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-04T09:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/10/04/post-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>End of Week 3</h1>

<p>I feel like we&rsquo;re really getting into things now and am trying to think ahead so that I&rsquo;m not wondering &lsquo;where did the time go?&rsquo; once we get to December. I miss this place already.</p>

<p>Stackworld was a lot of fun this week. My favorite part was the interaction, that there was more to it than typing a few things and just looking at the output. I was able to customize the player pages a bit and felt really good helping others do the same. For once I wasn&rsquo;t poking around trying to see who could help me, instead a few guys were gathered around my screen to look at the code. I spent some freetime creating rooms and have more of the world planned out.</p>

<p>I barely got any prep work done this week. I&rsquo;ve been too tired by the time I leave that I can&rsquo;t concentrate on anything else. Even reading the web-scraping info last night was taking longer than it should have. I&rsquo;ll take another look at Ruby Bits where I was stuck, and possibly the Treehouse Ruby tomorrow.</p>

<p>Maybe at some point I&rsquo;ll look into a comments section for the blog.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/number-6/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T16:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/number-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Number 6</h1>

<p>While waiting for 1-on-1 chats to continue I focused on Codecademy&rsquo;s Ruby work. If I can get more of the general concepts under control, I&rsquo;ll have an easier time with anything Ruby-related rather than the specific tasks needed for the exercises. While the exercises are a good way to prove what I know by putting my knowledge to use, there&rsquo;s not so much knowledge available right now. I&rsquo;m working on the Object-Oriented Programming I section with classes and being able to read about them while practicing the lesson in repl seems to be working.
As frustrating as things can get I kept in mind that I only need time to work at my own pace (while hoping that I don&rsquo;t become severely out-paced by the curriculum). Regardless of how my learning progress compares to the rest of the class, I&rsquo;ll get things done. This downtime has already proved to be very worthwhile and there is still an hour before I go in for the chat.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/number-5/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T09:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/number-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>End of Second Week</h1>

<p>Today completes our second week at Fullstack Academy. I am enjoying my time here and have not re-thought my decision to leave my job in order to dedicate myself to the program. This is also my last day at the hospital which once again means I will have to leave early and skip some of whatever plans are in store for us.</p>

<p>I was able to contribute more to our group projects this week which I was happy about. It was more like figuring out patterns and repeating them for different parts of the program rather than knowing what to do from the beginning, which leads to my next topic:</p>

<p>Sleep. I will now have a normal sleeping schedule which should help me stay awake in class. I worry that my learning capability has been hindered these two weeks and I miss out on time to complete the prep work. Even Sunday afternoon I found myself watching the same videos and re-reading paragraphs because I couldn&rsquo;t focus.
I still need to figure out Ruby classes and their relation to methods and instances. The information is mine for the taking, I just need to figure it out. In 12th grade I couldn&rsquo;t get a grasp on physics until studying for the midterms in January or February, though I plan on getting things done within the week, not five months.</p>

<p>Going upstate tonight but if anything I&rsquo;ll bring some Ruby and JavaScript books for the train.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fourth Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/fourth-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T09:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/fourth-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fourth Post H1
Looks like the third post didin&rsquo;t send to the correct place but I can see it in the preview, along with an updated theme.
I enjoyed my week here at Fullstack and am looking forward to the rest of my time here.
Some of the Ruby has been difficult. While I didn&rsquo;t do most of the testing, it didn&rsquo;t look so difficult when we went over the problems and I was able to see how the programs ran. I think that with time I will become more aware of what Ruby can do and how to make it happen. I have since begun the Haiku project, which doesn&rsquo;t seem as difficult as I had initially thought. It all comes down to getting Ruby to do what I need it do. All that&rsquo;s left for me is to find the right commands.
Pair programming worked out well. I liked being a part of a team and it was interesting to see how Vin and Scott think in relation to the code. I found that Vin and I had a more similar approach. I am interested in working with the rest of the students but feel I should be more prepared next time, in order to contribute more to the code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Email Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/19/email-update/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-19T15:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/19/email-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Working on Ruby to send email out to users on a given list in regards to updates of this blog. Adding another post to help with testing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/second-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T12:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/second-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Getting a lot farther now</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T11:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the second try of the first post H1</p>

<p>I had a problem getting Rails set up last night but it worked today when Nimit tried. Still doesn&rsquo;t look like things are going to work but I will try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
