<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-27T09:58:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://SBlines.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/number-5/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T09:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/number-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>End of Second Week</h1>

<p>Today completes our second week at Fullstack Academy. I am enjoying my time here and have not re-thought my decision to leave my job in order to dedicate myself to the program. This is also my last day at the hospital which once again means I will have to leave early and skip some of whatever plans are in store for us.</p>

<p>I was able to contribute more to our group projects this week which I was happy about. It was more like figuring out patterns and repeating them for different parts of the program rather than knowing what to do from the beginning, which leads to my next topic:</p>

<p>Sleep. I will now have a normal sleeping schedule which should help me stay awake in class. I worry that my learning capacity has been hindered these two weeks and I miss out on time to complete the prep work. Even Sunday afternoon I found myself watching the same videos and re-reading paragraphs because I couldn&rsquo;t focus.
I still need to figures out classes and their relation ot methods and instances. The information is mine for the taking, I just need to figure it out. In 12th grade I couldn&rsquo;t get a grasp on physics until studying for the midterms in January or February, though I plan on getting things done within the week, not five months.</p>

<p>Going upstate tonight but if anything I&rsquo;ll bring some Ruby and JavaScript books for the train.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fourth Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/fourth-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T09:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/fourth-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fourth Post H1
Looks like the third post didin&rsquo;t send to the correct place but I can see it in the preview, along with an updated theme.
I enjoyed my week here at Fullstack and am looking forward to the rest of my time here.
Some of the Ruby has been difficult. While I didn&rsquo;t do most of the testing, it didn&rsquo;t look so difficult when we went over the problems and I was able to see how the programs ran. I think that with time I will become more aware of what Ruby can do and how to make it happen. I have since begun the Haiku project, which doesn&rsquo;t seem as difficult as I had initially thought. It all comes down to getting Ruby to do what I need it do. All that&rsquo;s left for me is to find the right commands.
Pair programming worked out well. I liked being a part of a team and it was interesting to see how Vin and Scott think in relation to the code. I found that Vin and I had a more similar approach. I am interested in working with the rest of the students but feel I should be more prepared next time, in order to contribute more to the code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Email Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/19/email-update/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-19T15:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/19/email-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Working on Ruby to send email out to users on a given list in regards to updates of this blog. Adding another post to help with testing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/second-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T12:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/second-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Getting a lot farther now</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T11:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://SBlines.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the second try of the first post H1</p>

<p>I had a problem getting Rails set up last night but it worked today when Nimit tried. Still doesn&rsquo;t look like things are going to work but I will try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
